Thomas O. Alake

 No 84, Peace Community, CMCM, Bashiri Ado Ekiti, Ekiti State, Nigeria.
☑ alakethomas65@gmail.com
☑ (+234) 703-319-4145

VOCATIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

Pastoral Assistant, Pope John Paul II Pastoral Center | Ado Ekiti, Nigeria | Feb. 2018 – July 2018

Worked as an administrative and personal assistant for Ekiti Diocese Bishop, and coordinated workers at his residence.

- Assisted with the Bishop's program scheduling and management
- Oversaw Bishop's court maintenance
- Tutored students in Catholic-run secondary schools in the state capital
- Supported addicts going through recovery
- Ensured the welfare of the church community

Pastoral Assistant, St Patrick's Catholic Cathedral | Ado Ekiti, Nigeria

| Aug. 2017 - Jan. 2018

Worked with the Parish Priest to ensure smooth running of daily programs and managed the Cathedral inventory.

- Supervised workers at the Cathedral and the mission house and ensured maintenance of facilities
- Taught and graded students on church doctrine
- Made provisions for individual, group, family, and children counselling on themes like mental awareness, morals, healing, and self-awareness.
- Took leadership role in the execution of outreach and ministration programs designed specifically to promote inclusion and pain alleviation within the community: mainly through regular group visitation to hospitals, checking the mental wellness and giving words of encouragement to patients
- Counselled church members, visited and provided support when needed
- Oversaw members welfare, including visiting the sick and helping with financial or housing assistance
- Coordinated charity events that catered for the needy in the community
- Assisted the cathedral administrator with document filing, appointment bookings and program scheduling
- Documented money inflow and outflow

Pastoral Internships | Ekiti, Nigeria

|2012, (2014 – 2017, July to Aug.)

Had a full year internship at Ifaki Catholic Parish in Ekiti state, Nigeria, from 2011 to 2012, where I worked closely with the priest while learning leadership, financial management, program coordination, counselling, mentorship and other general social work skills. In subsequent yearly two-month internships, while undergoing my philosophy program, I practised all I had learned in the prior years in the parishes I was posted. I led church services, organized and carried out social work programs that focused on family and children. I sourced donations for the welfare of members, resolved dispute between/among members and families, and gave counsel when necessary. I provided spiritual and psychological support for the church community, and collaborated with different societies in the church, especially St. Vincent de Paul to promote charity, welfare and social work duties of the church.

EDUCATION

University of Benin (In affiliation with Seminary of All Saints, Uhiele, Ekpoma) | Edo State, Nigeria

| June, 2017

Bachelor of Arts in Philosophy

Thesis: A critique of Sidgwick Henry's Moral Utilitarianism

Veritas University | Abuja, Nigeria

| August 2022

Bachelor of Arts in Christian Theology

dachelor of Arts in Christian Theology

Thesis: Covid-19 Pandemic as a Theological and Pastoral Issue: A Case Study of Veritas University, Abuja

c	ı,	ш		·
3	ĸ	ш	L	LS

AWARDS AND CERTIFICATIONS

Languages: English (fluent), Yoruba (Fluent)	Partial tuition waiver, Veritas University, Abuja Nigeria 2020-2022	
	Jobberman Soft-Skills Training Certification 2021	
Communication, active listening, empathy,	Certificate of Acknowledgment for Philosophy June 2017	
critical thinking, problem solving, organization, teamwork, and attention to details.	Participant, Inter- Religious National conference Veritas University, Abuja, Nigeria May 2022	

OTHER EXPERIENCES

Visited Osiomo leper hospital to care for the disabled	April, 2013
Rendered assistance to orphanage home through Child Welfare Services	August 2017 – June 2018
Summer Holiday Teacher, Sacred Heart Parish Ibadan, Nigeria	November 2019
Mental health secretary and assistant at Gender Studies and Counselling Unit, Veritas	October 2021 – August 2022
University Abuja, Nigeria	

REFERENCES

Dr. Peter Kamai	Lecturer, Department of Theology, Veritas	+234-803-6514751	janibanibu@gmail.com
	University		
Prof. Michael Udeopko	Dean, Faculty of Humanities, Veritas	+234-814-7806048	ufokism@yahoo.com
	University		
Dr. Barnabas Shabayang	Head of Department, Theology, Veritas	+234-803-3183707	Bsbliss93@gmail.com
	University		